《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on prison break
我直说吧
Let me get this straight.
两兄弟又回来了 离监狱15里
The brothers come back to a city that's 15 miles from the prison
他们从这逃出去的 干吗又回来?
they escaped from--why would they do that?
或许是因为总统要来芝加哥演讲
Maybe it's because the president is in Chicago to make a speech
他们要来这搞点事
and they're up to something,
从法律上来说 这带子毫无用处
Legally speaking,this tape is useless.
我们要挟她
So we blackmail her.
要挟她做什么?
In exchange for what?
总统特赦
A presidential pardon.
现在 你是准备为了已经到手的钱大呼小叫
Now, are we gonna keep crying about money you've already got coming to you?
还是想办法赚更多的?
Or do you want to make some more?
我听着呢  去过墨西哥么?
I'm listening.  Ever been to Mexico?
什么时候上吃的? 我饿了
When's the meal coming around?I'm starved.
有机会让我爽一把 亲爱的
Freshen me up when you get a chance, darlin'.
费尔南多!
Fernando!
蒂亚
Tia!
蒂亚 这是玛丽克鲁斯
Tia, ella es Maricruz.
－我会为你包管这包裹的 先生   －哦 不
I'll check this bagfor you, sir. -Oh, no.
我要随身带 给我
That's coming withme-- give it back.
先生 我想这包裹一定是超重的
Sir, I know that bag is way over the weight limit.
给我吧  保证安全
Sir, your bag will be safe.
他们看着你的
They're watching you.
但是从哪呢?
But from where?
那里
There.
莱娜斯总统毁了你们 也毁了我
President Reynolds ruined your life; she ruined my life.
你们想让那婊子好看么
You want to take that bitch down?
你们找到同伙了  就是现在了
You just found your inside man, but it's got to be right now.
－这两人有登记入住么? －是的
Have either of these men checked in? -Yeah.
10-06 房间
Room 10-06.
待会儿 你会在牢里收到个包裹
Later today, you'll get a package in your cell.
是我寄的  我要你使用里面的东西 行么?
It's gonna be from me-- I need you to use it. Okay?
打开4号门!
Open on four!
来帮帮忙!
I need a hand in here!
叫医生  在B－4房
I need a medic  in B-4!
让我死
Let me die.
不
No
让我死
Let me die
大量的人群集结在芝加哥市中心的博特蒙大街
A large crowd is gathering along Beaumont Avenue here in downtown Chicago
他们是来欢迎凯若琳 莱娜斯总统的到来的
anticipating the arrival of President Caroline Reynolds
今天她来到了卡莱尔大酒店继续进行巡回演讲
who continues her speaking tour today with an appearance
总统靠近南面警戒线了
Inner Circle approaching the south perimeter.
1号警卫
Marker One.
2号警卫
Marker Two.
3号警卫
Marker Three.
好了
Okay.
我想你该走了
I think you'd better go.
－你确定? －是的
You sure?  -Yeah.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help,
但是 呃 你也不能为我们做更多的了
but, uh, there's nothing more you can do for us.
就这样离开好像不太好吧
It doesn't feel right,just leaving.
我想你不会想要来趟这混水的 谢谢你了
I don't think you want any part of this. Thank you.
十分钟就到了  是吧?
It's ten minutes away, right?
至少十分钟
At least.
听着 如果这办法行不通的话
Listen, if this doesn't work,
我们最好想好后路
we're gonna need a way out--for good.
那就要看你的了
Well, that's on you.
是的
Yeah.
那德里克呢?
What about Derek?
德里克 斯维尼? 是的
Derek Sweeney? Yeah.
你认为他会来么? 是的
You think he'll be up for this? Yeah.
好吧
All right.
这地方你熟
This is your neck of the woods.
你想在公园会面么?
You want to meet at the park?
呃... 拉辛大街和第三大街交界处如何?
Uh... how's Third and Racine?
拉辛 第三大街?
Third and Racine?
呃... 3点15分 角落处
Uh... 3:15, the corner.
我会到那的
I'll be there.
如果有意外的话...
If anything happens...
...我爱你们俩
...I love you both.
坐下
Sit down.
他们何时在这 5分钟前 还是10分钟前?
When were they here,five minutes, ten minutes?
他们根本没来过
They were never here.
不不不 他们就在这 我知道他们在这
No, no, no, they were here.I know they were here.
他们去哪了?
Wh-Where did they go?
我不知道
I don't know.
不 你知道的
No, you do know.
他决定了这样是最好的
He decided it was for the best,
而我无法再忍受
and I couldn't take this anymore.
你们就这样玩完了?
It's over just like that, huh?
－是的 －那你还用那个死了的女的身份
-Yeah.It's overlike the time -you flew to New Mexico on dead woman's ID to meet up with him?
飞去墨西哥见他?
Or it's over like the time that you met up
或者和他在埃文斯车站碰头并且一起回来?
and got back together at the train station in Evansville?
又或者像今天那样
Or maybe like the day, today,
2小时前一起入住这宾馆?
when you checked into this hotel here two hours ago?
这些事里面哪个算是玩完啊?
Which one is it like, like that?
说实话 你信不信我都无所谓
I don't honestly care if you believe me or not.
你们没打算见面 还是根本没打电话?
No plans to meet,no phone calls?
－我说的是真话 －他不会给你电话么?!
I'm telling you the truth. -He's not going to call you?!
别对我撒谎
Don't lie to me.
你会后悔的
You don't want to do that.
打扰下
Excuse me.
能告诉我那标签什么意思吗?
Can you tell me what the sign means over there?
我不明白
I'm just wondering.
无申报出口
No hablo granjero.
嘿!
Hey!
嘿 你干吗?
Hey, hombre!
你是谁?
Gue haces?
我需要电话
I need a phone
给我电话 听我说 必须是今天!
Listen to me, man,it needs to be today.Shh!
嘿 听着 我家人有麻烦了 行么?
Hey, look, my family is in trouble, all right?
外面有个人要伤害我家人
There's man out there who's trying to hurt my family.
你家人没事
Your family is fine.
没人会伤害你家人
There's nobody after your family.
不 你看着我
No, look at me, man.
听着 我不是疯子 行么?
Look, I'm not crazy, okay?
我知道规矩
I know the rules.
要不是紧急状况的话我不会求你
I wouldn't be asking you if it wasn't an emergency.
求你了 让我用下那电话
Please, just let me use that phone.
求求你了
Please.
兰探员
Agent Lang.
是 是 请让马宏听电话
Yeah, yeah, I-I need to speak to Mahone, please.
让他打回给你行么?
Can I have him return?
听这 我是本杰明 迈尔斯 富兰克林
Listen, this is Benjamin Miles Franklin,
我现在就得和马宏谈
and I need to speak to Mahone right away.
富兰克林打给马宏的
It's Franklin for Mahone.
我来接
I'll take it.
富兰克林先生?
Mr. Franklin?
我是惠勒探员
This is Agent Wheeler.
我想我们不认识的吧
I don't believe we've met before.
我要找的是马宏
I need to speak to Mahone.
有什么可帮你的么?
Something I can help you with?
听着...
Listen...
我要给他留个口信
I want to leave a message for him.
告诉他...
You tell him...
我会做他要求我做的事 行吗?
you tell him that I'll do what he wants me to do, okay?
我需要点时间
I just need a little bit more time.
但我一定会做
I'll do it.
别伤害他们
Just don't hurt them.
听到了吗?
You hear me?
别伤害他们
Don't hurt them.
什么事?
What's up?
失陪下
Excuse me.
怎么-- 你疯了?
What the-- Are you crazy, man?
你他妈在这干吗? 小声点
What the hell are you doing here, man? Keep your voice down.
小声点
Keep it down.
最近如何?
How you been?
还好吗? 看见你太好了 老兄
You all right?It's good to see you, man.
我也是 兄弟
You, too, brother.You, too.
如果有谁知道你在这儿
Look, if some of the guys knew you were here,
他们谁都不会悄悄的...
they might not be too cool...
知道 我不是来逛的 我要你帮个忙
Well, I ain't hanging around; I need a favor.
你欠我人情
You owe me.
是的 我欠你的
I-I do. Y-You know I do.
我只是...
Look, it's just...
只是你现在的处境实在是
Look, it's just your situation right now.
我是说 我刚有了个孩子 小男孩
I mean, I just had a kid, a baby boy,
我答应过玛丽...
and I promised Marie...
我不是来着找麻烦的
I didn't come here to cause trouble.
我没有多少朋友  我要找个靠得住的.
I'm short on friends;I need to hook me up.
你是唯一能帮我的
You're the only one who can do it without the green up front.
我说真的
I'm serious about this, man.
这个  我需要这个
Here. I need it.
好吧
Okay.
我尽量
I'll give it a shot.
什么时候   越快越好
By when?   ASAP.
明天? 后天? 现在
Tomorrow? The next day?  Now.
现在
Now.
好吧  林肯
All right, Linc.
跟我来
Come with me.
我们有磁带
We have the tape
有人看见他被抓住吗?
Who saw him go down?
媒体记者? 我们动作很快
Any press?We got him down pretty quick,
但是不知道
but you never know.
是不是有人拍到了照片
Somebody may have gotten a shot.
去查查看
Check around.
必要的话
Confiscate cameras
没收相机
if you need to.
在谣言散布之前发表一个声明
Put out a statement before rumors get started.
让所有人都出去
And get everyone out of here.
马上
Now.
我们还在等候上头命令
We're still waiting for the response from Counter...
你我都清楚
You and I both know that
现在的形势不允许我们循规蹈矩
this situation requires us to abandon protocol.
我不管你要怎么跟他们说
I don't know what you need to tell them,
但是现在我要你的人离开
but I need your men to leave.
立刻
Now.
是
Yes, sir.
你哥哥在哪?
Where's your brother?
－我要见总统   －真的吗?
-I need to see the president. -Really?
你觉得可能吗
And you think that's a possibility?
她一定想要知道我要说的事
She'll want to hear what I have to say.
哦 鬼才信呢
Oh, I highly doubt that.
能跟你说话的人...
The only person you get to talk to...
...只有我
...is me.
想活过下一刻的话
And the only way you're going to live through the next hour
就告诉我怎么找到你哥哥
is if you tell me where to find your brother.
好吧
Okay.
他在一个安全的地方
He's in a safe place.
说准确点
Be more specific.
准确的说...
Specifically...
是个你永远找不到的地方
a place you will never find him.
我非常有幸... 加入过
I had the honor... to attend
这个国家最著名的军事学院（西点军校）
this country's most prestigious military academy...
它的使命是
whose mission it is
训练 鼓励
To educate, encourage,
激发年轻学生军官
and inspire the Corps of Cadets,
让他们用品质和智慧带领着国家的军队
so that each graduate is acommissioned leaderof character,
效忠于荣耀 自由  和国家
committed to the values of honor,freedom and country
但是 最重要的是 他们教会了我这个
But, first and foremost,they taught you this
你们西班牙语里"樱桃"怎么说来着?
How do you say "cherries" again?
Cereza.
看来你得多弄些樱桃（Cereza）回来
Looks like you have to get more cerezas.
宝贝  我刚给了你100个阿月浑子（一果实）
Baby, I just got you 100 pistachios,
加了足够的盐
with the right amount of salt, too.
是啊 它们得一起搭配着吃
Well, it's the combination.
我两种都要
I need both.
我为什么对你这么着迷呢?
Why am I a sucker for you, huh?
什么? 她说什么
What? What's she saying?
看起来像 帝博格
That looks like T-Bag.
嘘
Shh.
他说他正想从机场偷走行李
He said he was trying to steal luggage from the airport,
但是...
but...
他拿走了五百万  他怎么还要...?
he's got $5 million. Why would he...?
除非他没有钱
Unless he doesn't have it.
除非他的钱在那儿
Unless he lost it there.
等一下 费尔南多  什么?
Stop it, Fernando.What?
你真的认为
Do you really believe that
那些钱在机场?
that money is at the airport?
嗨  忘了它吧
Hey, forget it.
看看我们现在一起拥有的
Look at what we have together.
你想再为那个冒险吗?
Do you really want to risk that?
我们有我们要的一切
We have everything that we need.
除了你的樱桃（cerezas）
Except your cerezas.
对了
Right.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
费尔南多...
Fernando...
我会马上回来
Hey. I'll be right back.
你应该知道
You got to know
对我来说 看出你是瘾君子并不难
it's not real hard for me to recognize a junkie.
我   我  我
I'm... I'm... I'm...
我是说 你看起来不太好
I'm saying you don't look so good.
我没事
I'm fine.
你服用的那是什么?
You mind me asking what you're taking?
你也想要吗?
Here. You want one?
不 算了 -给你
No, that's okay.-Here.
留着以后能用
Save it for later.
福拉特儿
Varatril.
那可是苯甲酸镇静剂
Benzodiazepine's a hard-core tranquilizer, man.
你每天都服用这个?
You take these every day?
20毫克的剂量
20 milligrams.
你一定感觉飘飘欲仙
You must feel like you're walking underwater.
确实是这样
I do.
有一种安祥的感觉
It's very quiet down here.
就是这样 是吗?
That's why you started, right?
安静无忧的感觉
Peace and quiet.
不是仅仅因此你才磕药的吧 是吗?
That's not why you do it anymore, though, is it?
现在只是头痛?
Now it's the headaches, right?
也许你也睡不好觉
And you probably don't sleep.
你也知道
And you know
你会毁了你自己的 知道么?
you're going to destroy yourself, right?
我并不排除这种可能性
I haven't ruled that out as a possibility.
希望尽快得到你男友的消息
I hope we hear from your boyfriend.
我和马宏有一个区别
There's one difference between me and Agent Mahone.
他根本不清楚
He doesn't know
你的价值
the value of a bird in the hand--
他不停的旁听侧击
he just keeps beating and beating around that bush.
但如果你不交出布伦斯 我可不在乎
But if you don't give up Burrows, I don't care.
你们都得死
One down, one to go.
我想和斯科菲尔德先生单独谈谈
I need to talk to Mr. Scofield.
总统女士...
Madam President...
我能...
could I...
和你谈谈吗?
have a word?
让斯科菲尔德和你单独在一起
It wouldn't be prudent for me
会很危险的
to leave you alonewith Mr. Scofield.
我的人就在门口
My men are right outside this door.
我有我的隐私权
I have a right to privacy.
你的权利与我无关
Your rights aren't my first concern.
要不要我提醒你你在和谁说话?
Do I need to remind you who you are talking to?
出去
Step outside,
并记得把门关上
and close the door behind you.
你为你哥做的一切挺感人的
The things you do for your brother.It's impressive.
你又何尝不是如此
I could say the same for you.
但我不说风凉话
But I won't.
你听着 你的建议什么都不是
Bear in mind, your opinion means little to me.
这盘磁带
This tape.
现在在你身边吗?
You have it with you?
不在
No.
但我可以安排让你听下
But I can arrange for you to hear it.
你没资格为我做安排 斯科菲尔德先生
You don't make arrangements for me, Mr. Scofield.
我的人会的
I have people for that.
我甚至怀疑
I'm not exactly sure
这盘磁带里的内容
what is on this tape
但我总感觉里面有点什么
but I doubt it's of any interest to me.
里面是一段
It's a recorded conversation
你和你弟弟的对话
between you and your brother.
我和我弟弟一生中
Well, out of millions of conversations
打过无数电话...
that I had with my brother during his lifetime...
你说错了
I'll narrow it down for you.
那是在他"死"后你们的对话
It was recorded sometime after his death.
而这段
And this
重要的对话...
particular conversation...
能让你保全你的家庭
you might want to keep in the family.
它在哪里?
And where is it?
20种不同的拷贝
20 different copies
分别在20个不同的地方
in 20 different locations.
我现在就能打电话给我哥哥
I can call my brother right now.
他能播放给你听
He can play it for you.
不能在电话里
Not on the phone.
让他带着磁带到这里来
Have him bring it here.
这是我的条件
These are the terms.
要么在电话听到
You can hear it over the phone,
要么在新闻里听到
or you can hear it on the news.
由你决定
It's up to you.
我知道我是怎么开始的
I know it's why I started.
开始什么?
Started what?
吸毒
Using.
和你的原因一样
Same reason as you.
什么原因? 是因为你在医院实习期间得熬夜?
Why, because you had to stay up all night during residency?
还是因为在所有女生面前
Because the bass player dumped you
你的乐队男友把你当众甩了?
in front of the whole sorority?
你和我真的有很多共同点
Yeah, you and I got a lot in common.
我也见到过人的死亡
I've seen people die, too.
我想不是你杀的吧
I'm assuming you didn't make them die.
你需要帮助
You need help.
这不是我所需要的
Not what I'm looking for.
为了你好 希望你男友快点打来
For your sake, I hope your boyfriend calls back real soon.
蒂亚?
Tia?
玛丽克鲁斯?
Maricruz?
人都去哪了?
Where the hell is everybody?
妈妈
Mami.
看哪! 这不是苏克雷嘛!
Hey... lookie here, good ol' Sucre.
你对他们做了什么?
What did you do to them?
他们在哪里?  玛丽克鲁斯!
Where are they? Maricruz!
你冷静点
Hey, hey, hey, hey, keep your cap on.
他们去摘苹果了
They're out picking apples for the Snuffleupagus.
如果你...冷静点!
If you ever...Calm down!
他们随时都会回来...
They're going to walk back in here any minute...
这就会引起麻烦
which means trouble.
除非你想让我
Now, unless you want
看到你女朋友穿内衣的样子
to see me try out the new T-20Z on your bella muchacha, Mari-poon.
...你最好跟我走
...I think you'd better come with me.
你好?
Yeah?
林肯 布伦斯?
Lincoln Burrows?
卡罗琳 莱娜斯
Caroline Reynolds.
我知道
I understand
你有东西给我
you have something for me.
还在吗?
You still there?
是的
Oh, I'm here.
现在终于听到你说话了
It's good to finally talk to you.
在那242个挣扎在死亡线上的夜晚
Wish I had the chanceone of those 242 nights
我都希望有机会和你谈谈
I spent on death row.
请你播放那盘带子
Please just play the tape.
我知道这很糟糕
It's awful, I know.
但我们已经作出决定了
But the choice was clear.
你必须离这儿远远的
You needed to be far awayfrom all of this.
我是啊
I am.
我在特伦斯岛上
I'm the Isle of Terrence,
大海的远处
far off to sea.
我还是在你身边的
Look, I'm still here for you.
不要总想着坏的方面
Now, listen to me, don't dwell on the negative.
有的人注定要这样的 卡罗琳
Some people deserve to dwell, Caroline.
我和你只有一个电话的距离
You know I'm only a phone call away.
还有3000英里
And 3,000 miles.
你...
Do you...
你知道
Do you know
这里有多冷吗?
how cold it is here?
我们已经谈过这个了 特伦斯
We talked about this, Terrence.
你会很孤独 但只是暂时性的
You knew that you would be lonely, but it's only temporary.
对他的指控已开始移交审理
His appeals process has started already.
比你想象中的还快
This is gonna fly by quicker than your 20s.
不久人们就会淡忘他
And soon the world will forget all about him
他们也会淡忘你的
and they'll forget about you, too.
我答应你
I promise.
但...
But...
见不到你真让我痛不欲生
it's killing me not being able to see you
亲爱的卡罗琳
sweet Caroline.
我也很想见你
I want to see you, too.
但现在真的不行
But that can't happen right now.
这栋房子很大
This house is so big.
我只是想着你...
I just think of you...
躺在床上...
lying in bed...
我知道 我也是
I know. Me, too.
你的温存...
Your warmth...
你的触摸
your touch.
他走的很痛快吗?
Was it quick when he killed himself?
比我父亲的死痛快多了
It was a lot quicker than how my father died.
他们射中了他的背
They shot him in the back.
他死在我的怀里
He died in my arms.
我只想知道发生了什么
I just want to know what happened.
你弟弟向我们道歉
Your brother apologized.
他说他很抱歉
He said he was sorry,
然后就打穿了自己的脑门
and then he blew his brains out all over the wall.
那一瞬间 他没有感到痛楚
It was quick.
那是他自己的抉择
And it was his decision.
现在 该是你做出选择的时候了
And now it's time for you to make yours.
不 不 不
Nah, nah, nah, man.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我绝不能这么做
I can't do that.
你可以
Yes, you can.
没有什么好怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of.
我想你不明白
You don't get it, do you?
你阻止不了这个家伙
You can't stop this guy.
没有你的合作我是阻止不了
Not without your cooperation,I can't,
可是如果你肯告诉我
but if you talk to me,
如果你肯把事实都说出来
if you tell me what's going on,
我可以帮你
I can take care of you, okay?
你必须相信我 富兰克林先生
You've got to trust me,Mr. Franklin.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
西诺 对吧?
C-Note, right?
随便你
Yeah. Whatever, man.
我只要你告诉我
All I need you to do
马宏对你所说的一切
is tell me exactly what Agent Mahone told you.
只要你告诉我马宏的事
If you give me Mahone,
我就会让你拥有你想要的人生
I'll give you your life back.
不瞒你说 神真的是站在我这边
God's been smiling down on me, I can tell you that.
首先 我在阿尔戈马逮到了哈威尔
First, I caught up to Haywire up in Algoma.
不过在他们把他带走之前
He did a swan dive off a grain elevator
他便跳塔自杀了
before they could put him away,
但是奖金我还是拿到了
but I still get the reward.
等等 等等 他死了?
Wait, wait, wait. He's dead?
没错 就像只不堪一击的小虫
Yep, like a gnat on a Peterbilt.
但愿你不会步他的后尘
Hope you don't take the same route, Sucre.
绝不 我还不能死
Oh, hell no, I got plenty reasons to live.
我想你还舍不得福克斯河吧
I hope a few of them are in Fox River.
如果你肯乖乖听话
Or maybe, if you play nice,
我说不定会施舍几块
I'll throw your Maricruz a couple bills
给你的玛丽克鲁斯
after I turn you in.
抓到我你会得到多少钱?
How much are yougetting for this?
十万
A hundred grand.
你肯定想不到你个猪头还值这么多吧
I bet you never thought your ass'd be worth all that.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait.Wait.
要是我说能帮你弄到那五百万呢?
What if I know where you can get five million dollars?
是真的
You heard me.
在哪?
Where is it?
如果你不把我带回美国
I could take you there,
不把我送回监狱的话
if you didn't have to take me back to the States
我就告诉你
and turn me back in.
在哪里?
Where is it?
帝博格就在这镇上
T-Bag's in town.
我早在以前承诺过
I made my commitment a long time ago.
我一定会
I agreed
永远把国家放在第一位
to put my country ahead of myself,
就像母亲奉献给孩子一样
like a mother does for a child.
我以为
And I thought that
我所做的一切都是崇高的  并且...
what I was doing was noble
有一天会得到回报
and that I would be rewarded.
你错了
You were wrong.
难道你看不出我也不过是个棋子?
Don't you see that I'm a pawn in this, too?
权力已经像癌症一样侵蚀了这个国家
The power that has taken over this country is like a cancer,
而且完全无法阻止了
and it will stop at nothing.
我已经无能为力
It is out of my control.
此事也是如此
So is this.
告诉我你到底想要什么
Tell me what you want from me.
解开手铐
Uncuff me.
我没有钥匙
I don't have the keys.
那就去拿
You'll get them.
然后 我要你让我在无任何监视的情况下
Second, I want you to arrange for me to walk away alone.
一个人离开这里
No surveillance.
好
Okay.
最后...
And finally,
我要一个总统赦免
I want a presidential pardon for me and my brother,
完全赦免我哥哥和我
fully exonerating us of all our crimes.
我今天就要
And I want it today.
我不可能这样
I can't just hand out pardons
想赦免谁就赦免谁
to anyone I choose.
这是有程序和规定的
There is a process,rules.
这也不例外
This is no exception.
你将收到一份文件
A document will be delivered for your approval
就和一般的赦免文件一样
just like any pardon.
你签了它
You'll sign it
然后转交于律政署
and then file it with the attorney general
他们会将其记录
who'll submit to the presidential record.
好 我签
Fine. I will sign
你要我签什么就签什么
whatever you need me to sign.
很好 但是你我都很清楚这还不够
That's very kind, but we bothknow that's not enough.
你还想怎样
What do you want from me?
我会亲自把你放走
I will unlock you myself, walk you out of here.
难不成 还要我送你去机场?
What, you want me to drive you to the airport?
我已经不像以前一样那么轻易信人了
I guess I'm notas trusting as I used to be,
尤其是对那些一纸文书
especially with paperwork.
太得不偿失
It's so easy to lose.
所以 我要你趁这个现场直播的机会
No, I want you to go out there
在所有人的面前宣布
in front of everyone
对于我们的完全赦免
and announce our full pardon on live TV.
你疯了
You're insane.
事情不是这样
That is not the way
就能解决的
things are done.
人们会起疑心
This is not a vacuum--people will ask
－会问问题   －赦免!
-questions.  -Pardon!
现场
On stage.
现在
Now.
那..那我怎么确定
And-And how do I know
事后你不会公布带子?
that you won't release the tape an hour later?
你确定不了
You don't.
你唯一能做的就是相信我
You'll just have to take my word for it.
我需要更多保障
Well, I need more than that.
你是不会得到的
Well, you're not going to get it.
凯若琳...
Caroline...
是时候了
it's time.
赶快决定吧
Make your choice.
亚当斯 帮他解开手铐
Adams, I need you to uncuff the detainee
然后把他带到这
and bring him here
让他走
to be released.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我将会宣布
I am going to make an announcement
斯科菲尔德和他哥哥无罪并让他安全离开
pardoning Mr. Scofield and his brother, and he will walk away unharmed.
你疯了吗?
Are you out of your mind?
他已经将一些无可争辩的证据暴光了
He has brought some indisputable evidence to light.
我们马上就可以结束这一切了
We could end this all right now.
而你却想让他们就这么给溜了?
And you're gonna let them walk?
不要忘了  我是总统而你只是个奴才
am the commander in chief, and you are a corporate lackey.
现在我要去发表演说
I am making the calls now;
你没有任何权力来干涉
you have no authority.
我的人会把斯科菲尔德先生送走
My men will see to it that Mr. Scofield walks away
不许你和你的手下碰他一下
without the interference of you and your pit bulls.
你一个人吗?
You alone?
是的
Yeah.
事情办好了吗?
How'd you do?
三张船票 同一个船舱的 单程
Three tickets, one cabin, one way.
太好了
Nice.
算我欠你个人情
I owe you.
不用  我们扯平了
No, we're even.
这是给你的  谢谢
These are for you.  Nice.
还有这个
And this.
这是什么?
What's this?
你逃出来后 埃迪用100块和我打赌
Eddie, when you broke out,bet me a hundred bucks
说你过不了一周就会被抓回去
you'd be caught in a week.
我说  不可能
I said, "No way.
我认识的林肯绝不会这么差劲
Not the Linc I know."
所以  我想和你平分这一百块
Figured I'd split it with you.
可以了么?
So this is it, huh?
恩
Yeah.
祝你好运
Good luck.
多加保重
You take care.
你也是    好的
You, too. All right.
你会没事的
You be safe.
这地方你熟
Your neck of the woods.
好  拉辛大街和第三大街交界处怎样?
Yeah, how's Third and Racine?
我会去那儿的
I'll be there.
我不想这么做  真的不想
I don't want to do this,I really don't.
你在...你在说什么?
What are you, what are you talking about?
但是你不能说  我没给过你机会
But you can't say that I didn't give you a choice,
而你  你知道  你从未
but you, you know, you never
弃暗投明...
take the easy way, you...
而且我发现你  你...
And I noticed that about you, you...
我并不希望事情变成这样
I didn't expect it to be any different
但这是我的工作
but I have a job to do,
是工作迫使我这么做的
a job that I'm being made to do.
接电话  莎拉
Pick it up, Sara.
莎拉  接电话
Sara, pick it up.
快接电话!
Pick up the phone!
等等  等等!
Wait, wait!
别动
Don't move.
听着  呃... 别  别动
Just, uh... don't, don't move.
好的  我需要那个电话  把电话给我
Okay, I need the phone.Give me the phone.
待在那儿别动
Stay right where you are,
你不是真的想这么做吧
You don't really want to do this.
你不知道我最想做什么
You don't know the first thing about what I want.
收到我的短信了吗?
Get my message?
是的
Yeah.
我看到她了
I got her.
她跑出来了
She's on her way out.
跟着她  她会带你找到  斯科菲尔德的
Follow her; she'll take you right to Scofield.
先生...我们得谈谈
Sir... we need to talk.
再过几分钟
In just a few minutes,
总统就会对
the president is going to announce a pardon
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德  宣布特赦
for Burrows and Scofield.
就象我们都知道的那样  这是一种背叛
As you're well aware,this is quite a departure.
她一向都很合作
She's always been willing to play ball,
但是我认为我们应该采取点行动了
but I think we need to take some sort of action.
先生...
Sir...
我也不希望打搅您  但是我不知道
I hate to disturb you,but I'm not sure
您是否知道她这么做的严重后果
you realize the gravity of what she's about to do.
迈克尔
Michael.
莎拉  她同意了
Sara, it worked.
特赦吗?
The pardon?
她随时都会宣布的
She's announcing it any minute.
哦  我的天啊
Oh, my God.
哦... 哦  天啊 迈克尔  真是不可思议
Oh... oh, my God.Michael, that's amazing.
快点过来  好吗?
Just get here, okay?
我现在在...
I'm on, uh...
高地
Highland.
一个杂货店  一直沿着河往南走
It's a warehouse.It runs right down to the water.
哦  好的  我这就过来
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm on my way.
我们成功了
We did it.
是吗?
Yeah?
恩...
Um...
兄弟 你的脸怎么了?
What happened to your face, man?
如果你想搭顺风车的话
If you want to take the ride...
就得付出点代价
...you got to buy the ticket.
是啊  没错
Yeah, right.
德里克帮我在货船找了个舱位
Well, uh, Derek hooked us up with a cabin on one of those freighters.
经五大湖到南美的
South America via the Great Lakes.
我们不需要那个了
We're not going to need that,
但是真的很感谢他
but, uh, this is appreciated.
再问一次  兄弟
One more time, bro.
我们成功了?
We did it?
没错
It's done.
我们成功了
We're done.
我  呃
I, uh,
我真想看看她当时的表情
I wish I could have seen the look on her face.
不  你看不到了
No, you don't.
哦  不  我真想看看
Oh, yeah, I do.
真让人难以置信
Unbelievable.
她就要宣布了
She's going to do it.
真是难以置信
Unbelievable.
总统现在马上就要在
The president is now taking the stage here
卡莱尔酒店发表讲话
at the Grand Carlisle Hotel.
推迟了两个小时是因为
The two-hour delay in her appearance
新闻秘书长 赖安博格对
due to an investigation characterized
过分狂热者 的一个调查
by Press Secretary Ryan Berg as "an overzealous fan."
你不是真想这么做吧
You are not going to do this.
恐怕是的
I'm afraid I am.
你要知道 之后后果如何
There are some developments you need to be aware of.
我已下定决心
I have made my decision.
拜托别再来问我
and I would appreciate you not second-guessing me.
我想你还没弄明白
I don't think you understand.
我们同样知道你的秘密
We know your secrets, too.
而且可以轻而易举的揭发出来
And we can reveal them just as easily.
你自己想想  孰轻孰重
You need to ask yourself who you fear more,
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德  还是我们?
Michael Scofield or us?
你还有30秒
You got 30 seconds.
你自己看着办吧
I won't keep you.
全世界都等着呢
The world is waiting.
还有十秒
Ten seconds.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎美国总统出场
the President of the United States.
九  八  七
Nine, eight, seven.
六  五
six, five,
四  三  二  一
four, three, two, one.
感谢你们耐心的等了我一个下午
Thank you for waiting so patiently all afternoon.
要不是你们  我的家乡父老
If it were not for the support of this great state,
伊利诺斯州  人民的支持的话...
my home state of Illinois...
谢谢
Thank you.
我今天就不会
I would not
站在这里了
be here today.
这也是为什么  我要选择在今天
Which is why I have chosen today
宣布这个重要的决定
to make this very important announcement.
有件事情
A situation
已经被人们逐渐的了解到
has recently come to light,
而且我也感觉到  我必须要采取一些行动了
and I feel that I must take action.
作为这个伟大国家的总统
It is my job as president of this great country
当我知道真相的时候  就要做出理性的决定
to make rational decisions when I am given facts.
而这种决定会惠及我们每一个人
Decisions that are best not for me, but for the people.
所以经过了再三的考虑
And so, after much consideration,
我很遗憾的通知大家
I regret to inform you
我被诊断出患有严重的恶性肿瘤
that I have been diagnosed
导致了癌症
with a highly malignant form of cancer.
基于此缘由  我将不再适合
And because of that reason, I am no longer fit
作为一个领导人  为大家服务了
to serve as your commander in chief.
为了这个国家的利益
In the best interest of this country,
我宣布这项决定  即刻生效
effective immediately,
我将辞去总统的职务
I am stepping down as president of the United States.
如果她不是总统的话 那盘带子就毫无用处了
If she ain't the president, the tape's useless.
也不可能特赦任何人了
She can't pardon anyone.
我们落空了
We got nothing.
现在我们唯一能做的事 就是
There's only one thing we can do.
我们得消失...
We got to disappear...
永远消失
forever.